Let's see how NumPy does arithmetic operations on arrays.
我们来看 NumPy 是怎么给数组进行算术运算的
NumPy allows element-wise operations,
NumPy 能进行元素范畴的运算
as well as matrix operations.
也能进行矩阵运算
In this video, we will only be looking at element-wise operations.
本视频只讲元素范畴的运算
Consider these two rank one arrays.
来看这两个秩为 1 的数组
We can perform basic element-wise operations using arithmetic symbols or functions.
我们可以用算术符号或函数来完成元素范畴的基本运算
Both of these forms will do the same operation.
这两种办法能实现的运算是一样的
The only difference is that if you use this function approach,
唯一的区别在于 如果用的是函数
the functions usually have options that you can tweak using keywords and methods.
那你可以用关键字和方法对函数进行调整
Let's also try element-wise subtraction, multiplication, and division.
我们再来试试元素相减、相乘和相除
Again, these also have the function approach.
这些操作也可以通过函数实现
In order to complete these operations,
为了完成这些运算
NumPy sometimes uses something called broadcasting.
NumPy 有时候会用一种叫 “广播” 的机制
Broadcasting is a term used to describe how NumPy handles
“广播” 一词在此处指的是
element-wise arithmetic operations with arrays of different shapes.
NumPy 对不同形状的数组进行元素算术运算的处理过程
An important thing to note is that,
注意
since we are doing element-wise operations,
因为我们在做的是元素范畴的运算
the arrays being operated on must have the same shape or be broadcastable.
所以相关数组必须具备相同形状或是可广播的
We'll talk more about this in a minute.
等下我们会具体讲这一点
Let's perform the same element-wise arithmetic operations on rank two arrays.
对秩为 2 的数组的元素进行同样的算术运算
Again, remember that in order to do these operations,
重申一遍 要进行运算
the arrays being operated on must have the same shape or be broadcastable.
相关数组必须具备相同形状或是可广播的
Here are two two-by-two matrices.
来看这两个 2 x 2 矩阵
Let's do the same arithmetic operations using the symbol notation.
我们可以用符号进行同样的算术运算
We can also apply mathematical functions such
也可以用数学函数来进行运算
as square root to all the elements of an array at once.
比如用 sqrt 求数组所有元素的平方根
Here's that rank one array we were using before.
这是之前那个秩为 1 的数组
We can get the square root of each element like this,
我们可以像这样求出各元素的平方根
and the exponential of each like this.
或像这样求出各元素指数函数的值
And also, each element to the power of two.
也可以求出各元素的平方
Another great feature of NumPy is its statistical functions.
NumPy 的统计函数也是一大特色
Statistical functions such as mean,
如平均值 mean 等统计函数
provide us with statistical information about the elements in an array.
能让我们了解数组元素的统计信息
Let's see some examples.
我们来看些例子
Here is that rank two array again.
还是这个秩为 2 的数组
We can get the average of the matrix like this,
我们可以像这样求出矩阵的平均值
as well as the averages of individual rows and columns like this.
也可以像这样求出各行和各列的平均值
We can do the same for statistics like the sum,
同理 我们还可以求其它统计数据 如总和
and others like the standard deviation,
标准差
median, maximum, and minimum.
中位数、最大值、最小值等
Finally, let's see how NumPy can add single numbers to
最后 我们来看 NumPy 如何在不使用复杂循环的情况下
all the elements of a NumPy array without the use of complicated loops.
增加 NumPy 数组各元素的值
Here's our rank two array again.
还是这个秩为 2 的数组
We can add three to each element like this,
我们可以像这样给每个元素加 3
and subtract three from each like this.
像这样让每个元素减 3
Multiply each by three,
每个元素乘以 3
and divide each by three.
每个元素除以 3
In the examples above,
上述例子中
NumPy is working behind the scenes to broadcast
NumPy 会在幕后对 X 数组广播 3
three along the X array so that they have the same shape.
使数组和 3 的形状相同
This allows us to add three to each element of X in just one line of code.
因此我们只用一行代码就能给 X 的各元素加 3
Subject to certain constraints,
一定条件下
NumPy can do the same for two NumPy arrays of different shapes.
NumPy 可以对不同形状的两个 NumPy 数组进行同样的操作
Consider this three-by-three array Y,
以这个 3 x 3 数组 Y
and this one-by-three array X.
和这个 1 x 3 数组 x 为例
If we do Y plus X, this adds zero,
如果让 Y 加 x
to the first column in Y, one,
那么 Y 的第一列会加 0
to the second column in Y,
第二列会加 1
and two, to the third column in Y.
第三列会加 2
As before, NumPy is able to add a one-by-three array to
与之前一样 通过将小数组广播给大数组
a three-by-three array by broadcasting the smaller array along the big array,
NumPy 实现了给一个 3 x3 数组加上一个 1 x 3 数组的操作
so that they have compatible shapes.
因为广播机制 所以两者形状兼容了
In general, NumPy can do this provided that the smaller array,
总结起来就是 小数组
such as the one-by-three array,
比如这个 1 x 3 数组
can be expanded to fit the shape of the larger array,
必须能扩展成与大数组兼容的形状
so that the resulting broadcast is unambiguous.
避免广播的对象模棱两可
We can do the same with a three-by-one array.
我们可以对 3 x 1 数组进行同样的操作
This adds zero, the first row of Y,
这会给 Y 的第一行加 0
one, to the second row of Y,
第二行加 1
and two, to the third row of Y. Checkout the NumPy
第三行加 2
documentation for more information on broadcasting and its rules.
更多广播知识及规则请查阅 NumPy 的文献